[
    {"question": "1.  Which of these countries did NOT fight in WWII?", "ans1": "Finland", "ans2": "Greece", "ans3":"Ireland", "ans4":"Italy","correctAns":"Ireland"},
    {"question": "2. Who is considered the Father of Communism?", "ans1": "Joseph Stalin", "ans2": "Fidel Castro", "ans3":"Karl Marx", "ans4":"Chairman Mao","correctAns":"Karl Marx"},
    {"question": "3. What is the longest that an elephant has ever lived? (That we know of)", "ans1":"17 years", "ans2":"49 years", "ans3":"86 years", "ans4": "142 years", "correctAns":"86 years"},
    {"question": "4. What is the name of this symbol: Â¶", "ans1":"Fermata", "ans2":"Pilcrow", "ans3":"Interrobang", "ans4":"Biltong", "correctAns":"Pilcrow"},
    {"question": "5. Around how many people did Soviet Union leader Joseph Stalin have killed for the good of the state?", "ans1":"5 million", "ans2":"40 million", "ans3":"100 thousand", "ans4":"20 thousand", "correctAns":"40 million"},
    {"question": "6. The results seen by countries ruled by communist governments have?", "ans1":"been exactly like the peaceful utopia for all described by Karl Marx.", "ans2":"ended in mostly peaceful ways for the citizens of these countries.", "ans3":"resulted in the deaths of over 100 million people.", "ans4":"created prosperity for the poor.", "correctAns":"resulted in the deaths of over 100 million people."},
    {"question": "7. Who was the biggest mass murderer in the history of the world?", "ans1":"Adolf Hitler (>15 million - Holocaust)", "ans2":"Joseph Stalin (40 million)", "ans3":"Vladimir Lenin (3 million)", "ans4":"Mao Zedong (45 million people - The Great Leap Forward)", "correctAns":"Mao Zedong (45 million people - The Great Leap Forward)"},
    {"question": "8. During the 1950's, United States foreign policy was characterized by?", "ans1":"increased trade with Communist China", "ans2":"an alliance with the Warsaw Pact nations", "ans3":"economic aid to the Soviet Union", "ans4":"efforts to block communist expansion", "correctAns":"efforts to block communist expansion"},
    {"question": "9. One way in which the Korean War, the Vietnam War, and the Persian Gulf War are similar is that in all three wars:", "ans1":"the goal was to defeat the Soviet Union", "ans2":"the United States was primarily interested in protecting oil supplies", "ans3":"the United States was fighting without allies", "ans4":"no formal declaration of war was made by Congress", "correctAns":"no formal declaration of war was made by Congress"},
    {"question": "10. Since World War II, what has been a major goal of United States relations with the Middle East?", "ans1":"a peaceful resolution to Arab-Israeli conflicts", "ans2":"an end to European influence over Arab nations", "ans3":"establishment of United Nations control over the Middle East", "ans4":"equal access for all nations to the oil reserves in the Middle East", "correctAns":"a peaceful resolution to Arab-Israeli conflicts"},
    {"question": "11. Which of the following is NOT an important element of communism?", "ans1":"No private ownership", "ans2":"Government controlled education", "ans3":"Government controlled factories", "ans4":"Freedom of religion", "correctAns":"Freedom of religion"},
    {"question": "12. Who was the leader of the Bolshevik Revolution who brought communism to Russia?", "ans1":"Joseph Stalin", "ans2":"Vladimir Lenin", "ans3":"Mikhail Gorbachev", "ans4":"Karl Marx", "correctAns":"Vladimir Lenin"},
    {"question": "13. What is the name given to the non-fighting war between the west and the Soviet Union to prevent the spread of communism?", "ans1":"War of Words", "ans2":"Battle of the Superpowers", "ans3":"Cold War", "ans4":"The 100 Years War", "correctAns":"Cold War"},
    {"question": "14. What war did the Communist Party of China win in order to take control of mainland China?", "ans1":"The Vietnam War", "ans2":"World War II", "ans3":"The War of Hong Kong", "ans4":"The Chinese Civil War", "correctAns":"The Chinese Civil War"},
    {"question": "15. Who was the first leader of Communist China?", "ans1":"Mao Zedong", "ans2":"Sun Yat-sen", "ans3":"Deng Xiaoping", "ans4":"Zhou Enlai", "correctAns":"Mao Zedong"}
]